so the next homework question which is
class 8 talks about three different
types of meditation I say meditation
then I want to blow my nose I don't know
okay
then I remember the first meditation I
went to I was at Princeton and my friend
said you want to come to a meditation I
said yeah I I always heard about
meditation you know so it wasn't that
the university we went to someone's home
and I remember the guy we sat down and
I'm excited you know this is gonna be my
first meditation in my life and I said
what do we do and he said close your
eyes think about nothing close your eyes
think about nothing so I said okay you
know and I try to think about nothing
for about I don't know 15 minutes you
know they said okay finish there like
that's it yeah that's meditation then I
the I didn't meditate for many years
after that I thought oh this is this is
stupid you know think about nothing you
know so real meditation should have an
object okay
real meditation should have an object
the word for one of the words for
meditation mind is dition which means
the mind which is holding an object so
even the name in Sanskrit is the mind
which is holding an object it's the name
for meditation mind so to say there's no
object is silly okay
it's like saying rubber band is not
abandoned not made of rubber
is that the name means holes of them
holds the object okay all right
so there are three ways there are three
kinds of meditation okay and it depends
on your object okay first one and I
would say the easiest one is called
shotgun say shotgun
shotgun is very easy like this morning
and yesterday we did a very I think
beautiful meditation 13 steps we mix
three traditional meditations Donlin
exchanging self and others and there's
seven steps about seeing everyone as
your mother and there were thirteen
steps okay and Tim put them up on the
board and you know on on the projector
and we saw the thirteen steps so in the
first level of meditation you memorize
the thirteen okay and you don't have to
memorize the whole word you just some
word that you can remember okay so you
can teach you with your eyes closed you
can teach it with your eyes closed which
I cannot do I was using the computer did
you notice the computer stopped on the
last three I'm like it's easier if you
memorize
okay so shot gum
it's called review meditation and you
you go through a list in your mind oh
what's a step number one what's a step
number two what's a step number three
okay and you just review the thirteen
steps of the meditation or any any step
what are the six perfections you know
Momo
this is tibetan national food it's like
American hamburger okay when he calls
dumb sim symptom don't see Tim's Timson
okay it looks like that and I used to be
the cook for eight years okay
I was the cook not very good cook
because I had thinking about the book
and so anyway when you give one moment
on the plate and the person in it then
you say oh there's a to truth two
realities have two then they finish then
you say somehow then you put three then
they are getting a little bit sick they
say four truths for higher truth these
five past six perfections seven parts of
I upon eight molecules eight atoms in
the molecules nine steps of meditation
ten advanced perfections eleven kinds of
knowledge twelve links of The Wheel of
Life then they're like no no more
Buddhism what am I talking about that
you can do that with your meditation
shark ohm
what's the six perfections you know
what's the ten good deeds okay you can
check yourself I have a friend Jeffrey's
off from Taipei you know him he's a
great man very great man great teacher
and those of you who study buddy Guinea
one day we're driving in the car you
know and I said you know your name is
unusual five half of all Chinese people
have the same last name Wang Qiang Joe
okay not really
it's because it's all Kings names then I
said your name is Tony I never heard of
it you know he's like oh yeah I guess it
means the left hand the person of the
left hand you understand which is very
important in virtue Guinea very
important left hand person so I was like
wow anyway when I met him he was a small
manager at DuPont corporation and Human
Resources and then he started to every
morning he does shall go just
and I said what's the subject you know
did you pick the six perfections or the
seven parts of dog are you path or the
eight molecules who he said no no Gila I
do my schedule for the day twelve
o'clock one o'clock two o'clock two
o'clock and I visualize tonglen I you
know I I go through the meetings what
I'm gonna do what I'm gonna say how can
I be Bodhisattva all day I prepare the
whole day's work before I get go out of
the house and I do char gum okay then he
became the manager for all DuPont HR in
Asia I think he has 15,000 people under
him I understand that's charkham okay
right all right
second one is called check Olmstead
check oh yeah Chango means
problem-solving meditation okay then you
think about some problem you know I
think very often it can be some problem
you're having personal problem or some
goal you want to reach okay so you can
do chicken so it's a meditation you're
in meditation posture and you say okay
I'm having trouble with my I don't know
my wife's mad at me or my husband is mad
at me my husband is yelling at me he
cost me phantom in the kitchen and you
know I'm having some problems so how can
I work on that what should I do
you know and that's called Chico okay
second kind of meditation is problem
solving or I want to make 10 million
dollars next year so how can I solve
this problem or I want to see emptiness
directly okay which is easier than ten
million dollars okay
if you have the gardener okay so that's
the second kind of meditation so you get
the feeling already that all meditation
has an object there's no such thing as a
meditation which doesn't have an object
there's no such thing okay now the last
one is called yoga say Geoghan you don't
tell jokes during the meditation
okay so again got it we are both naughty
guys so we understand each other some
kind of radical are you I have to live
with these guys and say Joe calm Joe go
means put your mind on the object and
don't move don't move it okay so typical
is a visualization right you make a
picture of your teacher you look at your
teacher in the meditation and you don't
take your mind off the teacher or you
put your mind on the friend who is
having a problem and you keep your mind
on them and that's called Joko okay
single point in single object just one
object then all three are real
meditation okay don't think that that
Princeton University meditation is
meditation okay think about nothing
that's not meditation okay every
meditation is one of these three these
are the three skeins of meditation oh
all we learn may be hundred different
meditations in the monastery but all of
them fit industry okay
so learn them and now when I designed
the course number three ACI course
number three I wanted to do a meditation
course about meditation at that time 100
years ago
many people didn't know about meditation
especially in America
you know everybody's try to think about
nothing and a whole country they don't
know what some meditation and so I
thought it's important in the meditation
course to put a valuable object for the
meditation so the last two and a half
homeworks okay are about the object of
meditation okay I put a object of
meditation what was it
yeah it's a short long live okay it's a
short moment in densha guma right the
source of all my good okay so the object
I chose for the meditation was the steps
of a long room so which kind of
meditation is it it's kind of a shotgun
it's kind of an outline of the steps to
Buddhahood okay Lamia means steps to
Buddhahood when I was a kid we used to I
used to mow the lawn you know is
something you have to do in Arizona we
have big houses big lawns every house
has big lawn and we have to mow it and
that's why you have kids in Arizona just
someone to mow the lawn
so then sometimes my dad will buy a new
lawn mower you know and they will come
with a special instruction book how 14
steps how to put the lawn mower together
you know number one open the box number
two take this part so good together and
if you just follow the instructions you
get a good lawn mower then you can more
the lawn okay now when you're a kid you
never follow the instructions you put
all the pieces out there and say I think
this one goes here maybe this one go
this may be here go here who needs a
book
you know and if you do that with your
meditation you will get similar results
this lot more never work I don't know
what's wrong
one time I finished put the whole thing
together and there's one screw is left
then I like where's that screw girl I
said it's probably not important school
you know so I start the engine and it
goes gonna go
everything blow up you know that's how
your meditation will be if you don't
follow the Lamia okay okay don't don't
just make up some meditation okay
follow the there's a step invented two
and a half thousand years ago by Buddha
he invented loving and just follow step
by step don't do the a lot more extra
school three okay really I blew up the
lawnmower my dad was very angry okay so
don't blow up your mind step by step so
that's the mom room structure and that's
it
I chose for the meditation object
looking then I'm gonna answer some of
the homework questions for you and the
teachers during the teacher training
right team are gonna continue with the
Lamia okay but I'll do some homework
questions with you and then we'll have
write some real nuts what time would you
like to start there the boring policies
first but if we do the policy lastik and
get a good sleep tonight I'm kidding
okay let me finish this and I'll start
the policy okay all right mmm the
question on the homework is a trick
question
very rare
number y which of the five grade books
and which level of secret practice can
you find in the Lauren all of them said
oh of course
okay that supposed to be you put the
five grade books in your great great
five great subjects you put them on your
homework answer okay
let's try in order anybody want to try
it in the order get the Geisha course
hmm anyway raise your hand
okay I'm offering no money you go ahead
what's the first one
say in English yeah basically what book
do you know yeah I'd be somewhat
uncommon yeah okay and then lower middle
way they'll only get lower middle waist
for 12 years 12 years and then four
years good upper-middle way yeah for
years higher middle way text is entering
entering the middle way min away by by
Chandra Kurtz Masterton okay you got two
of the five and then two years on Abby
Dharma yeah good we can say yes and then
two years on vinaya nice yeah and then
interspersed every winter three months
on logic yeah
[Music]
[Applause]
you're lucky because usually he won't
give correct answer with no money but he
tonight he did okay yeah those so those
five great subjects lower middle way
higher middle way abhidhamma morality
and then logic they're all in the lumber
all of them are in the lahrman as far as
secret teaching both stages are in the
main room okay but very short okay
you're supposed to find a different
teacher for secret teachings but but the
books they are in there some information
is in there okay all right so long mem
is pretty cool all right
the the book we're going to use for
alarming meditation is called intense
yogi Emma saying and then sure karma
okay it means the source of all my good
all my goodness come from one person all
the all the good qualities you have come
from one person right and that's my
teacher spirit my heart Lama okay
it was written by jetsam couple okay and
he went to a monastery called rogering
which was founded by a tisha and his
student crompton J who never became a
monk he was a businessman one of the
greatest Lamas of history was a
businessman understand CSB and I'd like
to thank the CSP people for coming can
you stand up
[Applause]
Thank You Stanley analysis for these
guys they all have big big big
businesses okay and they are taking a
special course to use the great ideas in
their business and to help other people
in the world to learn they're all I'll
teach you some Chinese work say hi mom
hi mommy
toasty toasty akaash Kokoschka
toasty Koshka fat-cat gado-gado gordito
it means successful businessperson there
are super successful businessperson and
they are using these methods to improve
their business standard in their life
and when I met them they are all tired
all successful businesspeople and a
little bit here some I wasn't sure
they're pregnant or not then they
started to yoga then I started
dimensions they studied many many things
they worked hard and every morning they
make a phone call to each other to
support each other 6:15 I'm asleep
they are calling amazing and now look at
them they are very beautiful
so I'm very proud of my kids in changing
grandpa proud of you okay all right I'm
gonna skip over to the boring part okay
which is the policy okay
oh by the way the end of the story so
Coppa he went to that monastery 400
years before him was a great teacher
from India called Artesia who is 400
years after Trenton 400 years after Sh
when some came to China right then 350
years after Sh went on a tisha came to
West China and start to teach okay then
so copper was born 400 years after that
and he want to get the blessing of a
tisha so he went to the monastery
running to our teachers monastery and
there's a famous statue of Artesia and
some Kaaba pray at the bottom of that
statue and he got a vision of all the
teachers of the lamrim and because of
that later he wrote the big la même 1000
pages okay if you translate into English
it would be ten thousand pages okay we
can do it in a couple of weeks yeah just
kidding but he got this inspiration for
this small room complete a small memory
and its emphasis is that we need a
teacher okay how to find a good teacher
let's do it
just one thing okay I'm gonna steal the
good part Tim you teach the boring part
okay
he's like yeah I like this one the
emphasis of that book and this is the
last teaching for ACI tonight right
tomorrow some more than a gajanan right
okay the first part of that LOM room one
more instruction book is how to find a
good teacher how to find a good teacher
so what kind of person I should look for
when I want to find a good teacher what
should I look for okay then there are
two famous lists okay there are two
famous lists each one has five qualities
to look for okay how to find a good
teacher all right so here's the
guideline traditional guideline how to
find it what kind of teacher to look for
okay the first quality they keep their
morality okay they don't kill things
they don't steal things they don't cheat
with other people's wife or husband they
don't lie they don't like to split up
other people they don't say harsh words
your phone they don't waste time gossip
gossip gossip cat videos now everyone's
gonna go home and look at cat videos but
while you're watching the cat video
please don't think about monkeys okay
[Music]
they aren't happy when other people have
problems they aren't sad when other
people get something and most important
they do believe in karma
okay and they do believe in emptiness
and sambal sweet sauce okay so those are
look for a person who knows the ten good
deeds and they keep it
if they have body stuff of us and they
are keeping them
that's like yo chow with a sweet I think
how do you say on top now I'm getting
hungry
okay extra sweet on top if they have
body stuff of us and they are keeping
them super sweet okay if they have
secret vows
unbelievable delicious okay and they are
keeping their vows okay they're a good
person they don't hurt other people okay
okay second one they have good
meditation okay their meditation is good
you can't see their meditation right
maybe they are sitting very good and
they are having subtle down this okay
and they are spaced out maybe they are
sitting for three hours they are doing
nothing it's possible many people did
that they have no meditation object it's
possible but the person who's meditating
every day they are nice person and they
are compassionate person and they have
good focus in their business also they
are like laser gun you know their mind
is like when they meet Nagarjuna
they are like or when they meet business
problem with the tax department
they're just everything legal okay like
them their mind is so powerful they can
do anything they don't get upset
instantly there are focused people okay
so from the outside we cannot see if
they're really meditating or not but
from the behavior we can guess if they
are meditating or not okay if they seem
nervous
they can't focus they get angry easily
then whatever they're doing is not
meditation all right
third one
they have wisdom and they use it to
control themselves when they walk in the
kitchen and their husband says you're
stupid they go ye and they stop okay
they can't control themselves
okay with wisdom okay emptiness where is
the emptiness in the kitchen yeah
there's no husband who is not my fault
okay that's that's real emptiness don't
think that the Buddha see some other
emptiness it's not like that Oh guests
always talk about the husband in the
kitchen but I think Buddhist emptiness
is higher it's not okay it's very famous
debate in the monastery you know if the
wife see that the husband not there this
one I didn't do anything and if a Buddha
see emptiness is there better or worse
then the famous answer no both perfect
both perfect emptiness okay
Buddhist nuts okay put it as and have a
wife are okay maybe but has this perfect
his emptiness and the wife's emptiness
in the kitchen exactly the same it's a
very famous question in the scripture
okay exactly the same nobody who didn't
come from you is the same garden the
people that the Buddha man who threw
Spears at him tried to kill him with an
elephant okay
then husband who yells at the why both
are kung equal okay if you see one you
saw the other okay all right how many
qualities we got good number four they
have seen emptiness best is if they saw
it directly if there are you okay best
is if they have seen emptiness directly
that's best okay but even if they didn't
see emptiness directly they are a pen
expert and every time they go to
Singapore they teach the pen again
and then the Singapore people have a
nice nap during the pan just kidding
every time they go somewhere they're
always talking about the pen okay
so best as if the person saw emptiness
directly but even if they didn't they
understand the husband in the kitchen
they understand the pen okay they have a
good understanding intellectual of the
pen that's quality number four
okay quality number five they love their
student they love their student okay
it's possible you have a teacher who's
very intelligent very smart can explain
the gardener very well but doesn't love
the student really they'd like to show
how smart they are or how good they can
explain or they can use Sanskrit or
Tibetan but they don't really love me
they don't love the student then it's
not enough that's not a good teacher
okay there are many great teachers like
piano teachers who don't like the
student okay maybe you met one of them
my teacher loved me so much he bung also
okay now I said there's two lists of
five right here's the other traditional
this okay first one in our life we
always have a choice we can focus on the
world they'd learn or we can focus on
the spiritual life and you should find
someone who likes to focus on spiritual
night all gays la-tso cannot be a
businessman right
no that's not true at all okay the
greatest Buddhist masters in India were
all government officials and big
business people Kings okay the
colorchecker tantra tantra secret
teaching was made for kings
one tau 1 tau 1 tau okay the way of the
kings okay really
her program is called one town in
Guangzhou very cool so but when those
business people do business they are
helping other people to succeed they
call their business competition can I
help you I found a good worker do you
want them I will give them to you they
are crazy
businessmen right ok I got it
so it's not outside what's the business
it's the heart in their heart they are
following Karma they are following
spiritually ok so look for this kind of
teacher okay
sometimes that teacher on the outside
look very Buddhist and on the inside is
always thinking about how to make more
money right or how to sell more Dharma
book just kidding ok so sometimes look
like a businessman on the inside they
are Buddhist master and some people look
on the outside they are Buddhist master
but on the inside they're business ok so
try to find the one whose real master it
doesn't mean they are not doing business
or or they're not married or things like
that ok
think what is what is their heart is
their heart spiritual look for that ok
ok second one
we always have a choice in our life we
can focus on this life or we can focus
on other nice okay this life extremely
short okay according to Buddhism this
life is one second like that and then
all your future life billions and
billions okay and your past life
billions of billions this one is nothing
so don't worry too much about this one
get ready for the next one
if you tomorrow
okay something break in your cabin don't
fix it
leave it for soon on your going home you
you gotta come back in 12 months okay so
don't worry about the small thing if
you're going on a long trip for 12
months before you come back to your real
home at Diamond Mountain okay then don't
don't spend a lot of time on the you
know two hour go go fix your house in
China or fix your house in Russia or
Argentina Buenos Aires still in Buenos
Aires yeah so you know the future life
is much longer it's the real house okay
this life is like diamond cabin on the
last day just show everything on the
ground go sorry I'm just kidding okay
when you're going on a long trip you you
don't worry too much about smoking you
know okay we are all going on a much
longer trip in the future after this
life so focus on that one so look for
the teacher who talked about what's
going to happen after you die look for
that kind of teacher okay all right we
have another choice in our life we can
take care of other people or we can take
care of me right guess which one is a
good teacher
yeah they like to take care of other
people first okay there's a thing in
English if there's a bad expression in
American English it's called looking out
for number one number one's gonna be
number one
$10 at him Red Hot Chili Peppers still
dreaming come on
I'll play it for you Sly and the Family
Stone what's the name of that song you
figured out Tim you gotta play it for us
not the red hot chili pepper come on
that's three thumb night get you decades
right okay okay we I want this lie okay
I don't want the Red Hot Chili Peppers
[Music]
yeah I have to teach you everything I go
through I go through and there's a line
in the middle
okay okay okay if you want me to stay if
you want me to stay you'll remember it
wasn't that long ago all right
mmm tell me when you're ready
I'll teach more Buddhism okay all right
so they take care of other people before
themselves okay and that song is called
taking care number one number one here
it comes okay number four they are very
careful what they say what
the bass player always the most
important
[Laughter]
[Music]
that's your very out now
number was gonna be number one okay so
that's a lot you don't want number one
number one okay number four they are
careful what they say they are careful
what they do they are careful what they
think playing rock and roll is also
careful okay Yali promised me a band oh
my god she's so cool
six thousand people I'm looking forward
to it okay anyway now there are careful
what they say they are careful with it
they don't hurt people alright number
five they don't teach the students a
wrong path
okay they teach them seeds they teach
them seeds okay that's all they teach
correct okay so that's the beginning of
the lamrim that's the most important
thing in the mom room right what is it
how to find a good teacher how to find a
good teacher okay and be picky be picky
okay it's more important than getting
married okay you don't get married to
just anybody right you take your time
find a rich guy who's also handsome and
doesn't mess around with the other you
know you this you take your time when
you marry a handsome guy like Sugeng
right you try to catch all that handsome
guys then you takes again
right but uh but teacher you have to be
even more careful why that teacher gonna
be with you for many lifetimes okay you
are stuck okay yes Doug so take your
time check to ask many people ask many
people did you study with this guy this
lady yeah I studied with them are they
good
yeah except you know they steal your
money now I mean ask other people ask
other people like if you're gonna hire
someone to build a house for you or
something you will ask many people who's
honest who's not going to take my money
so when you find it when you take a
teacher so many people just go come on
this guy Lamas teaching let's go you
know okay he has a nice big hat
you know okay let's go don't be like
that
okay check check many days I teach I
want to talk to his teacher in Sumatra
he traveled for 11 months when he get
there he didn't go to his house he
started asking people to get references
is he good is he really good okay he
spent one year on the boat to go to
Indonesia Union then he when he land he
check him out you didn't ask him to
teach okay you check him out okay so
don't be sure to check out a teacher
okay don't be shy
dig dig into them find out all the
stories ask all the students okay
because this is a big relationship okay
this is your whole life to lose some
money is nothing to lose your lifetime
you cannot get it back okay no one can
give it back to you you don't have time
to to spend with a bad teacher okay you
have to find a good one okay take your
time
and don't I don't trust people they come
to me after one talk oh can I be your
student will you be my mom I'm like no
[Music]
ask me in two years you know some don't
don't jump quickly you know wait and
tell you check the person okay all right
I